# MATTHEW P. MOMJIAN

matthew@momjian.me

Philadelphia, PA https://momjian.me

#### STATEMENT OF PURPOSE

I am currently completing my residency in anesthesiology at the University of Pennsylvania. I have extensive experience in pre-hospital medical care and a dedication to learning, teaching, and leading through my diverse interests and talents. Providing emergency medical care in a high-volume urban environment has given me a deeper understanding of modern healthcare challenges. My current focus is on educating myself as an anesthesiologist and gaining exposure to various subspecialties in the field. I hope to gain experience that will serve me as I transition to medical practice as a faculty member of an anesthesiology residency program.

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

#### Hospital of the University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA

2024-Present

## Resident Physician, Department of Anesthesiology and Critical Care

Internship: Penn Presbyterian Medical Center.

#### Philadelphia College of Osteopathic Medicine, Doctor of Osteopathic Medicine

2020 - 2024

Step 1, Level 1: Pass. Step 2 CK: 274. Level 2 CE: 905.

DO Admissions Committee member; Peer Tutor; PCOM Ambassador; PASS Mentor; executive board member of: Emergency Medicine Club, Wilderness Medicine Club, Health Career Collaborative.

## Delaware Technical Community College, post-baccalaureate coursework

2019

## President's List

2010-2014

Franklin & Marshall College, Bachelor of Arts in Music

Cum Laude, Departmental Honors in Music, Honors List (5x), Dean's List, Marshall Fellow Independent Study: "Conducting Performance of Beethoven's No. 3, Yardumian's Armenian Suite."

#### PROFESSIONAL LICENSES AND AFFILIATIONS

Gold Humanism Honor Society (GHHS), member

American Society of Anesthesiologists (ASA), member

American Osteopathic College of Anesthesiologists (AOCA), member

Emergency Medical Technician (EMT), licensed by Pennsylvania, Delaware, and the National Registry

Basic Certificate in Quality and Safety, Institute for Healthcare Improvement

ACLS and BLS Provider, American Heart Association

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### MedSchoolCoach, Remote

2019-Present

#### Associate Director of MCAT, Master USMLE/COMLEX Tutor

Tutored pre-medical students preparing to take the MCAT or medical licensing exams.

Planned and provided lessons, identified areas for student improvement, coached critical reasoning.

#### Saint Francis Hospital, Wilmington, DE

2014-2020

#### Field Training Officer, Emergency Medical Technician III

Emergency ambulance care in a busy metropolitan system, operating as acting supervisor of 8 units. Full-time employee. Precepted over 20 new EMTs through a three-month field internship program. Taught departmental courses and proctored oral and practical boards.

### COMMUNITY SERVICE

## Marple Township Ambulance Corps, Broomall, PA

2011-Present

#### Secretary of the Board, Field Training Officer

Volunteered for over 2,500 hours at local ambulance service covering suburban Philadelphia.

As a board member, manage budget, teach public CPR courses, and assist with public outreach.

#### Armenian Missionary Association of America, Armenia

June 2022, July 2023

Participated in medical service project to operate a primary care clinic in multiple rural villages.

## Franklin & Marshall College Emergency Medical Services, Lancaster, PA

2011 - 2014

## Director of Emergency Medical Services, Chief of Operations

Supervised 25 providers, developed response policy with local 9-1-1 authorities, procured equipment.

Managed education, personnel issues, and retention, and created and proposed budget.

#### HONORS AND AWARDS

Mason W. Pressly & Oscar John Snyder Scholarship, PCOM Board of Trustees

2020-2024

Generous scholarship awarded on the basis of clinical excellence and academic merit.

Gold Award, Silver Award (2x), AACOM COSGP TOUCH volunteer service program Performed over 200 hours of volunteer service to the local community.

2021, 2022, 2023

Gold Award, Silver Award, PCOM Cultural Competency Program

2021, 2022

Attended events designed to increase our cultural awareness as future physicians.

#### Albert D'Alonzo, DO '56, Endowed Memorial Award

2022

Selected by PCOM Alumni Association to receive award to fund medical service project.

Unit Citation (4x), Saint Francis Healthcare Emergency Medical Services

2014, 2017, 2017, 2018

Given for outstanding patient care in extremely challenging circumstances.

Individual Citation (3x), New Castle County Department of Public Safety

2015, 2016, 2017

Given for the successful pre-hospital resuscitation and discharge of a cardiac arrest patient.

Life Member, Exceptional Duty, Marple Township Ambulance Corps

2015, 2023

Given for significant hours dedicated in service to the organization, with over 10 years of service.

Winner, Pennsylvania Department of Health, HeartRescue Project

2014

Created original video used to educate state EMTs in new "pit crew" resuscitation techniques.

Nolt Music Award, Franklin & Marshall College

2014

Given by the music department to recognize outstanding graduates and support original research.

#### PRESENTATIONS AND RESEARCH

Research

Canakis JP, Momjian MP, Yousefian F, et al. (2023). Building a community of experts in medication-assisted treatment (MAT) using the Project ECHO model. J Opioid Management. 2023;19(1):11-18. doi:10.5055/jom.2023.0755

Presentation Kalczynski JM, Lombardi CP, Momjian MP, et al. (2020). Measuring the Effect of a Resuscitation Academy on Out of Hospital Cardiac Arrest Resuscitation Rates. Second-place winner of Foundation for Osteopathic Emergency Medicine Poster Competition.

#### LANGUAGES

Native: English, Armenian.

#### SKILLS, HOBBIES, AND INTERESTS

My travels to over 25 countries have increased my appreciation for many distinct cultures and traditions. I enjoy many outdoor activities such as kayaking, hiking, and swimming. When I am not outside, I have developed skills in computer programming, have competed on robotics teams at an international level, and play multiple musical instruments. As a first generation American and U.S. citizen, my Armenian ethnicity is particularly important to me, and I continuously strive to bring my Armenian culture to my everyday life.